Rin.
Hmm?
What are you going to ask Santa-san to get you?
I haven't decided yet.
If you don't make up your mind soon, it'll be too late;
he has to travel really far to get here!
Oh, really...?
C'mon now, what is it you want the most?
A lop-eared.
You already have one.
He needs friends!
Good evening!
Sorry for being late...
It's no problem!
Rin-chan!
What's that?
Hmm?
It's a Christmas tree!
Wow...
What's in here?
Ah... Something to do with work, you know?
Can I put the tree together?
Yeah.
Hurry up, Daikichi!
Okay!
This goes on top, right?
Sure does.
Ah!
What's up?
We don't have a chimney, do we?
Santa-san will be able to find his way in, so don't worry!
All right, I'll unlock the door for him!
I'm tellin' ya, it'll be fine!
To Santa
Thanks for
the present.
What's with the carrot?
It's for the reindeer!
I'm turning this off, all right?
Just a little longer...
Santa-san only comes to the houses of sleeping children!
Huh?! Turn the light off, quick!
Yeah, yeah.
To Santa
Thanks for
the present
Rin
I really wanted to meet Santa too.
Rin, let's eat!
Okay!
Thank you too, Mr. Reindeer!