If your blood type is B, you should be extra cautious.
If left unchecked, things can degrade even further,
to the point where your very life is at risk.
Turn it off!
No shows about being sick!
It's nothing to be that scared of.
How about we take a bath?
Am I going to die, too?
Huh?
What're you saying? You're only six!
My bad.
Usagi
Drop
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow
ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
This is different than making a sacrifice
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
Something about it is different
nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit
batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
So I just don't get why
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
but your existence is now much more than just important to me
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
I don't cry because I'm hurting
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
If I can be with you, I'm happy
kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy
bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
And our days will be just as happy!
sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
Just wanna make you happy!
See you.
We really need to find another nursery soon.
The huge companies that all of the smart guys work at...
...are supposed to have their own daycare services and stuff.
But where on Earth does that actually happen?
Hey, Kawachi-san.
Hey.
Kawachi-san, did you meet someone?
What!?
You've been heading home pretty early recently.
It's not like that.
You always used to be on the last train home, though.
Last year you clocked up some pretty huge profits for the company.
At this rate, we'll...
That was just because I worked my ass off last year.
You can't expect those kinds of figures all the time.
It comes and goes. They don't call me "Daikichi" for nothing.
TL Note: In Japanese, "Daikichi" means "great fortune".
Kawachi-san...
Wait!
Ah, I'll take that.
Thank you!
Going to the fourth floor?
That's right. Are you doing as well as ever?
Not so much this year.
Actually, I've just been getting chewed out by him.
I guess I'm losing my hair over it.
Do a good job once, and you set the bar really high for yourself.
Um, Gotou-san...
You're a mother, right?
D-Don't act so surprised just because I'm small!
No, it's just that you're pretty thin. I was
wondering where you could've fit a baby.
Your guess is as good as mine.
My kid's already two...
Thank you. Put it here.
Would you like me to go with you?
It's fine!
Right...
See you!
Gotou-san's just as tough as always, huh?
It's a shame she didn't stay in sales.
She's been with the company a few years longer than I have.
And when she got pregnant, she willingly requested a demotion...
...so that she'd be able to make it home on time every day.
The office was full of gossip about what she had done.
What?! How long are you keeping her for?
We haven't really decided yet...
"Rin-chan", huh?
She's going through a bed-wetting phase right now.
It really seems to be getting to her.
Maybe it's psychological?
Ah, though kids sweat a whole lot,
and in the winter and autumn, that doesn't happen as much,
so they start needing to pee a lot more often.
Oh, yeah. I remember!
I was always told to use the toilet before bed.
I guess her mother must have had a lot on her plate.
I couldn't bring myself to ask her, even if I wanted to.
It's really important for a kid to have a mother, isn't it?
Hey! Men aren't supposed to complain.
Don't give up!
What were you up to today?
Picture books, staring contests and other stuff.
Sounds fun.
What was that for?
Rin, I'll whip up dinner right away.
The moon's fading away.
Mother-Child Health Record Book
Hello?
Is everything okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I don't mean with you.
Y-Yeah, she's fine.
Wait. Why are you calling?
Didn't you say that you didn't want to get dragged into this?
I can't very well stay out of it when I know she's with you.
I'm heading there for the weekend to look for clues about Rin's mother.
Right. Then call when the two of you arrive at the station.
Be sure she gets wrapped up in something warm.
Ah, and I'll call Haruko, too.
Her kid and Rin seem to get along well.
Ah, another car!
You look like you're having fun.
Yep!
We're here.
Hello.
Rin-chan, good to see you!
H-Hey...
Sorry.
We don't really have anything a young child would like.
She seems to like old people's food, anyway.
Right?
Had enough already?
Yeah...
Don't come and tell me that you're hungry later on.
I'm not very hungry.
Sorry for leaving leftovers.
Hello?
Sorry I'm late.
Man, what a pain.
I can't believe that damn family!
Onii-chan! You actually took her home!?
Yeah...
And now, the weather.
Today, we'll see warm sunlight all across the country...
...with reported temperatures two degrees higher than normal.
I'm just going to the bathroom!
I need to use the bathroom!
I can't go when you're sitting right there.
Is she always like this?
Nope. At my place, she talks a lot more than you'd expect.
And on the train, she was acting like she was on holiday.
But when we turned up here,
she found an old couple from the funeral who scared her.
Hey, what are you trying to accuse us of?!
You idiot! When she sees adults in a bad mood,
she thinks that they're mad at her.
That's right. I suppose a child would...
I'm sure the two of you were the same.
See? Even an insensitive blockhead like you had a heart, once upon a time.
I guess Rin just has her head screwed on a little better than yours.
Shut it, baldy.
Rin-chan, you like cat's cradle, don't you?
Hey, at least answer her.
Yeah...
You can have this.
Pretty...
Watch how Auntie does it...
"Auntie"? You're more like her grandmother...
She's not old enough to be a grandmother.
What a lovely child...
It's just because she grew up with really old people...
I'll show you how to do it, so watch closely.
My... Did I make a mistake?
Oh, dear...
This? A four-step ladder.
Oh, my!
A two-step.
An aeroplane.
A slide.
A diamond.
That's amazing!
Wow!
It's because this cord is so easy to use.
Did you make it?
That's right! I knitted it out of thin wool.
It has a much better weight than if you use the thread as it is.
That's right!
She's good with her hands, so we can teach her otedama, too.
TL Note: Otedama is a Japanese children's game involving juggled beanbags.
Hm...
You take your pinkie, and thread it through here...
L-Like this?
That's right!
One for a rattle.
Two for a wisteria tree.
What's with this? What's going on here?!
I could ask the same about what you're wearing.
Coming!
Who's that?
It's probably Haruko and her daughter.
Rin-chan!
Pretty! What are they called?
Otedama!
Thanks for today.
But it's kind of amazing that you're juggling a job and raising a child.
My husband hardly helps out at all.
Are you going to your granddad's after this?
Yeah, I figured there might be some clues about Rin's mum.
I guess so.
I definitely think it's important for a child to have her mother.
This is weird...
You could've at least left a will or something, Granddad.
Weren't you worried about Rin?
A modem?
I'm home.
W-What's that on your head?!
Reina-chan did my hair like hers!
Ah, now that you mention it, your clothes...
They're Kazumi-oneechan's.
Huh? Kazumi?
Mum, you can't dress a kid up in old junk like that!
Look! I knew they'd suit her.
W-Well, I guess it's okay...
If you put them on a kid today, they actually look kind of modern...
Did you find anything at your grandfather's?
No. Nothing at all.
I see.
In any case, I suppose it's best not to get
worked up and press Rin-chan for details.
Yeah.
You're doing really well.
Huh?
I suppose we never told you,
but your mother kept working even after you were born.
Huh? Wasn't she always a housewife?
When she was pregnant with Kazumi, she pushed herself too hard...
...and ended up in the hospital for a time.
And by the time she returned to work, she had been all but pushed out of her job.
Your mother was terribly upset.
And Kazumi was a newborn, and so tiny...
...that your mother often had to take time off of work or come home early.
And Kazumi?
Your mother put so much effort into raising Kazumi...
...that she ended up like she is now, as loud and rambunctious as they come.
Are you okay? Do you want Dad to drive you to the station?
It's okay. We'll get there on time even if we walk.
Can we come again?
She asked if we can come again.
Auntie will be waiting, so come by whenever you like.
Later.
W-What're you saying?!
Don't you think it'd be nice to give us a grandchild?
I could look after the baby!
You can't keep working and raise a child at the same time,
so the woman always loses out.
Besides, I still want to wear swimsuits, go drinking and...
Hey, Rin. Was there a computer at Granddad's?
Do you know what a computer is?
Yeah.
Did Granddad use it?
The maid used it.
He had a maid?
Masako-san.
W-What sort of person was she?
I don't really remember...
I hate Masako-san.
She hated me, and she always got mad at me...
She was scary, so I forgot all about her.
I see...
It's a bit late to be saying this, but it's tough trying to juggle a job and raise a child.
Sure is. Not a moment's peace.
Gotou-san, have you ever felt like...
...you've sacrificed yourself for your child?
You mean when I was demoted at the company?
Sorry, I know it's rude of me to ask, but...
Well, at the time, I thought it was for the best.
And everything turned out okay, so why worry?
But even if I felt that way, I'd never come out and say it.
You can't underestimate the power of words.
Um... "Kotodama", was it?
TL Note: "Kotodama" is an ancient Japanese belief that words and names possess mystical or supernatural power.
Was that answer too abstract?
No, I understand completely.
I hope you'll teach me lots more about children.
Ha! But your kid's much older than mine.
You should be teaching me, senpai.
Rin... You should've just woken me up.
But... It's sweat!
It doesn't matter what it is. It's fine.
Did you have a nightmare?
What's it like to die?
Are you going to die before me, Daikichi?
Sadness over Granddad passing away,
anxiety over what she'd do if I died...
...and her own fear of death...
So many things she couldn't sort out, all jumbled in the back of her mind.
You don't need to worry about that until you're a woman.
When will I be a woman?
No... You don't need to worry about it until you're an old lady!
I'm not going anywhere until then!
You can count on me.
Yeah...
And don't worry about wetting the bed.
Make sure you use the toilet before bedtime, and you'll be fine.
But going to the toilet is scary...
I'll go with you at night.
And even if you wet the bed, you just need to change.
Will you get mad?
It's nothing to get mad about.
And nothing to laugh at.
Yeah...
So what did you want to talk about?
I'm sorry to call you out on such short notice, Hiraka-san.
Huh?
This is going to sound sudden, but...
Please transfer me to a department where I won't be doing overtime.
Huh?! Kawachi, are you serious?!
Deadly serious!
I see, so that's what's happened...
Personally, I think it's extremely disappointing.
But I have children, too.
I'll try and put in a good word to the head of the department.
I'm sorry. Thank you for all your help.
But your subordinates aren't going to be pleased...
I can't accept that!
Why does it have to be you?
Couldn't you have asked another relative or something?
I probably shouldn't tell him that I took her in on the heat of the moment...
Besides, aren't there nurseries that watch children until late at night?!
I don't want to work under anyone except you, Kawachi-san!
I know it's sudden,
but the higher-ups shuffle around the company's hierarchy a lot.
There's no point in getting worked up about it every time!
But I'm really sorry...
Things will settle down in my department without me, eventually.
They'll be able to deal with a little reshuffling.
It'd be weird if an organisation couldn't.
But Rin is different!
Or at least...
I'm pretty sure I'm right to think so.
Probably.
Is it done?
Yeah. This much rice?
Yeah, that's just right.
Admittance Guide
Towel, lunchbox, indoor shoes, toothbrush, cup...
We've put your name on them, too.
What?! A futon?!
Oh, right. That's for the infants' class.
Right.
Daikichi, hurry up!
Right now, I'd be lying through my teeth
if I said that I wasn't sacrificing something here.
So I hope that several years down the line, I'll be able to.
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
where should we go today?
kyou wa doko hee yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
...shines with a dazzling light
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
and you by my side...
tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
Whoa! High, high, high!
My feelings are ready to burst forth
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice reaches every corner of the earth
koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
I'm already high, high, high!
mou high high high!
もう high high high!
Riding the whirling winds...
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice swoops up and down with me
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Hey Rin, that thing you have on your handtowel and lunchbox...
You know... The dog thing with the long ears.
It's not a dog!
It's a lop-eared!
Lop... What?
A rabbit!
Huh? It's not a spotty dog?
It's a rabbit!
Hmph...
Rin, go to the toilet first.
I already have!
Right.
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
Don't you want to be kinder?
Oh, I can't continue it...
Good afternoon, Rin here.
Right now I'm training for the sports meet.
I got much better at dancing!
Next time, or the time after that, I'll show you.
The next story is "Letter".
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
Episode 4
Letter